<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: language | Show & Tell]]></title>
  <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/language/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-11-05T17:47:01+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ThoughtWorks]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing a non-English Inception]]></title>
    <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/11/managing-a-non-english-inception/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T22:10:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/11/managing-a-non-english-inception</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following write-up is about some of our experiences while conducting an Inception for a client (Konvergence), where some of the participants are not comfortable (capable) of conversing in English. The intention of writing this is also for people who have had other varied experiences while running non-English Inceptions to share their thoughts/suggestions.
This was my first experience of such an environment and I was not sure about how we would be able to play this out on the ground.</p>

<h3>Pre-Inception</h3>

<p>We found out during our pre-inception catch-ups with the customer that there are some people (1 or 2) on the customers team who can understand English and can also help in translation. However, we were not able to judge whether they will be able to translate the messages during the long drawn out battle and whether the message will be conveyed as intended. We shared our concern with the customer and they proposed to use the (English speaking) members in their teams to translate the communications. We also built a lot of leeway in our plan to allow for the conversations and translations to go through smoothly, so if a session would normally take 60 mins we assumed that we would spend a minimum of 90 mins under these circumstances.</p>

<h3>During Inception</h3>

<p>The actual inceptions and discussions went more smoothly than expected, largely since most of the participants had some working knowledge of the language and were able to understand, also we had at least 4 people in the customers team who were fairly comfortable with the language and could help in translations. However, most of the conversations were relatively time consuming since after one of the facilitators presented something, the translators had to repeat the same. We also had to ensure that we spoke slowly and gave appropriate pauses so that the translator had shorter messages to process and translate.</p>

<h3>Some tips:</h3>

<p>  <em>Nice to have:</em>
  Try to pick up some words in the language and use them also try to learn a bit about the language. If the efforts are genuine they will be recognised and will help in building some trust with the translators and the non-English speaking participants.
  Try to use pictures and images in your sliders more than words since pictures (if put together correctly) can convey the universal message.
  Try to have someone in the facilitation team who can atleast understand the language so that the customer discussions can be understood.</p>

<p>  <em>Avoid:</em>
  Do not use google translate to translate your communication or slide shows. It is not always possible to convey the meaning through a plain translating of words and there is a high probability that you may end up saying something wrong or offensive.
  Don&rsquo;t lose your patience!!</p>

<h3>Some Mishaps:</h3>

<p>There were certain mi-communications that occured during the inception, for instance when we asked who will be providing the UX we were told that there is another firm that does this work. It&rsquo;s only later that we realised that this firm only did graphics, logos etc and had no experience in designing website or mobile applications. By then it was very late and we had to initiate a thread with TW staffing to get a UX expert. At this moment I am not sure how (given the circumstances) we could have done things differently to avoid this, but I haven&rsquo;t given up yet.</p>

<h3>Overall:</h3>

<p>Overall it was a very nice experience working with the Italians who I found to be really warm, respectful, helpful and extremely patient. We were lucky to have a few people on the client team who understood the English and were able provide fairly accurate translations. Also, we had people on the ground (from the Gruppo PAM) project who had met the client earlier and had some local market experience.  We may need a more comprehensive or different strategy for more challenging situations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
