<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughtworks | Hakawati]]></title>
  <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/thoughtworks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-11-18T12:17:00+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ThoughtWorks]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Live Below the Line Case Study]]></title>
    <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/11/live-below-the-line-case-study/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T18:44:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/11/live-below-the-line-case-study</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Region:</em> Australia</p>

<p><em>Industry:</em> SIP, Global Development</p>

<p><em>Capabilities:</em> CD,Cloud, Delivery</p>

<p>Live Below the Line is one of the fastest-growing anti-poverty campaigns in the world. An annual campaign run by The Oaktree Foundation (Australia) and The Global Poverty Project (United Kingdom, United States and New Zealand), challenges people to live below the extreme poverty line for five days to raise funds for projects aimed at helping the 1.4 billion people living in extreme poverty every day. ThoughtWorks took on the project that other consultancies said was impossible and launched the minimal site in 6 weeks using Contiunous Design and Continuous Delivery with short frequent releases.</p>

<p>The successful 2012 campaign had more participants (8000+) and raised more funds (over $2.1 million) globally than in the last 3 years combined. Through the support of ThoughtWorks Social Impact Program (SIP), the cost to develop the website was less than the ongoing comission they would have had to pay with the previous site.</p>

<blockquote><p>New website wanted. Fundraising and social networking skills, and a desire for continual new challenges required.</p></blockquote>

<p>The annual campaign website has been crucial to success, because in addition to letting people sign up, and accepting and processing donations, it provides resources and an online community space to aid participants in sticking with the challenge.</p>

<p>After three years of growth, the campaign needed to replace the website that had supported it so far as it no longer served participants or donors well, and the user experience was compromised due to a disconnect between the fundraising and community/resource aspects, that required multiple logins. New functionality necessary to the growth of the campaign was becoming increasingly difficult to add, and rising licensing fees, charged as a percentage of donations, were a concern.</p>

<p>Oaktree and Global Poverty Project jointly decided to invest in a custom built application: a cutting-edge integrated fundraising and community platform with social media integration. This would let them serve the growing base of donors and partners, take control of their intellectual property, provide the flexibility they needed for more projects and local features, and remove ongoing fees.</p>

<blockquote><p>No one thinks it can be done? We say “Let us show you how.”</p></blockquote>

<p>The organisation selected ThoughtWorks to develop the site—the only vendor willing to commit to the tight three-month deadline necessary to support the next campaign. Our team members were as motivated by the anti-poverty objective of the campaign, as by the technical and timing challenges of the project itself. Promotion of social and economic justice is one of the Three Pillars that underlie everything we do at ThoughtWorks.</p>

<p>A week-long inception was conducted at the outset, developing the product vision and creating a shared understanding of the campaign, website objectives, scope and priorities. Getting the site up and live with a minimal set of features was critical to kicking off the campaign as soon as possible, thus providing enough time to get the number of participants required to meet the fundraising goals for the upcoming annual campaign. The team decided to take a Continuous Design and Continuous Delivery approach and focused on the minimal viable product that could go live, including the appropriate amount of design to represent the brand.</p>

<blockquote><p>Designing and Community Building</p></blockquote>

<p>Designing a single solution presented a number of challenges due to the different ways the campaigns are run. The US and UK campaigns, for instance, run on a partnership model where not-for-profit organisations establish campaigns within the Live Below the Line website. Other regions do it differently.
Another key consideration for the new site was that it must foster a strong sense of community among participants, as that is extremely important to a successful campaign. Live Below the Line wanted participants to share their experiences with friends, and make friends in their online community. This meant, among other requisite features, member profiles and pictures, creating and finding teams, posting photos, blogs and links to YouTube and the ability for participants to comment on everything. Leaderboards for individuals, teams, workplaces, and others were implemented on the website in order to create a sense of competition, to boost the overall outcome of the campaign.</p>

<blockquote><p>Rails, the Cloud and Kanban accelerate development</p></blockquote>

<p>Ruby on Rails was used as the base of the technical stack, as its built-in capabilities and plugins would accelerate coding. Heroku, a flexible cloud-based hosting platform for Ruby applications, was selected to host the new site. With those decisions in place, developers started establishing the development, QA and production environments in parallel, and setting up the continuous delivery infrastructure.</p>

<p>Development proceeded using agile and Continuous Design techniques. The user experience design was created on a just- in-time basis for each development iteration, with the business team then giving feedback during each showcase of the working software. Using automated deployments and testing, updates could be made very quickly.</p>

<p>Kanban was used to manage requirements. With this approach, the team maintained a prioritised backlog of features to be developed. Developers pulled features from the backlog in priority order so the highest priority features are always being coded and tested during any given iteration. When “enough” new features were ready, the team made a decision to do an internal or external release.</p>

<blockquote><p>You need it in three months? How about six weeks.</p></blockquote>

<p>The first external release of the website came just six weeks after the inception, with a sufficient set of features, organisation branding, and user experience elements. The team had been working to launch in time for University orientation week, but late in the game the client realised they had made a mistake with dates. Could we move the release up?</p>

<p>We were able to release on the new date, thanks to the level of test and deployment automation and the reliability of the continuous delivery processes. We launched the new website in time for the first orientation week campaign.</p>

<p>Over the next nine weeks, 26 more releases to production were performed, with each including extra functionality and design changes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireballs In The Sky]]></title>
    <link href="http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/10/fireballs_in_sky/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T09:42:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://tw-uganda-blog.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/10/fireballs_in_sky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The TW Perth office released an Android/iOS app called Fireballs In The Sky to help encourage community involvement with the Desert Fireball Network, links below.</p>

<p>For the rest of you&hellip;</p>

<p>So, what do you do when you are approached to work on a project called &ldquo;Fireballs In The Sky&rdquo;?
Clearly, you ask where to sign.</p>

<p>How about if you&rsquo;re in a small office with no capacity, in a sold-out country?
Did I mention it was called &ldquo;Fireballs In The Sky&rdquo;?</p>

<h2>Tell me more!</h2>

<p>Such was the dilemma faced by the Perth office, but the prospect of some cool work, in a cool domain was too great to resist. With support from ThoughtWorks, the office signed up to do the project in their own time to get some cool local work we could reference.</p>

<h2>Who is it for?</h2>

<p>The project is part of a science outreach program from Curtin University, supporting the research of the Desert Fireball Network (DFN). The DFN is a series of cameras being spread out through Australia, to track fireballs and help determine their origin. More details can be found here: <a href="http://www.fireballsinthesky.com.au/about/.">http://www.fireballsinthesky.com.au/about/.</a></p>

<h2>Alright, so what did we do?</h2>

<p>It is an app designed to get people interested in the project and science in general. The app had to be, in the words of one Professor Phil Bland, &ldquo;cute&rdquo;.  The team at Curtin are able to keep the citizen scientists up to date with the latest events, news and sightings, and can share some of the amazing images taken from the DFN and other sources. The best bit though, is people being able to contribute their own sightings and even better than that, build their own fireballs.</p>

<h2>Did you just say build their own fireballs?</h2>

<p>You bet I did. In order for an engaging experience, the team picked up a few stories clearly not in the MVP pile to enable the users to describe their sighting with an animated fireball.</p>

<h2>Tell me about the greasy bits!</h2>

<p>The team initially spiked out using Calatrava, but the more we looked the less shared logic we had. Given the level of interaction needed with the sensors and wanting to make it &ldquo;cute&rdquo; on as many devices as possible, we discounted pure web. The answer? Two native apps.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Android</strong>

<ul>
<li><em>Targeting 4.0+</em></li>
<li>Android Tools w/ Gradle</li>
<li>Roboguice</li>
<li>ActiveAndroid</li>
<li>AndEngine</li>
<li>Retrofit</li>
<li>Jackson</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>iOS</strong>

<ul>
<li><em>Targeting iOS6+</em></li>
<li>Cocoapods</li>
<li>MagicalRecord</li>
<li>cocos2d</li>
<li>AsyncImageView</li>
<li>AFNetworking</li>
<li>BlocksKit</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Backend</strong>

<ul>
<li><em>Rails 3.2</em></li>
<li>ActiveAdmin</li>
<li>Heroku</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Other</strong>

<ul>
<li>TestFlight</li>
<li>Snap CI</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>How was the experience?</h2>

<p>Working with Curtin was great, really collaborative and nice to have an enthusiastic partner. To cherry pick two phrases from Phil at the app launch:
&ldquo;This went far beyond business, it was true collaboration.&rdquo;
&ldquo;The ThoughtWorks team went beyond with their skill, energy and ideas.&rdquo;
So, just who are you guys again?
The team consisted of Brad Ward, Ray Grasso, Mike Gardiner, Mark Togher and Nathan Jones, with cameo appearances from David Colls, Maia Sauren, Diana Adorno, Andrew Carr and the rest of you I&rsquo;ve likely left off.</p>

<h2>Gimme! Gimme! Gimme!</h2>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/1eZ68BA">App Store</a> &lt;&mdash; Share me!</p>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/1eK6X1S">Google Play</a> &lt;&mdash; Share me!</p>

<h2>I learn best through pictures.</h2>

<p>Luckily, here is a picture of the team!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fireballs_team.jpg" title="Fireballs Team!" alt="The Fireballs Team" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
